CARLOS GEOVANY PEREZ VELAZQUEZ

DATA ANALYST

PROFILE

I'm a skilled Data Analyst, Systems Engineer, Computer Technician and Programmer with more than 5 years of experience in Data related roles at large banking corporation and education institutions, national and international customers ranging from banking and insurance companies to top ranked universities. I'm a self-starter and have a thirst for learning.

CORE STRENGTHS

- · Detail Oriented
- · Technical Skills
- Analytical skills
- · Work Ethic
- Time management
- Fast Learner
- Teamwork

LANGUAGE

- Spanish
- English

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, HTML, CSS3, SQL, API's, Pandas, D3.js, Microsoft Azure Data Studio, Databricks, Scala, Power BI, Jupyter Notebooks, Web scraping, Topic Modeling, NLP, Machine Learning, Git, AWS, Microsofot Fabric

CONTACT

Mobile: (860) 377-2003 Email: ccggppvv@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/carlos-perez-

996249116

Web: https://carlosgeovany.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

SYSTEM ANALYST

Unisys, Mexico, 2015 to 2019

- Analyzes and evaluates user requirements, report requirements and system design problems.
- Trends of systems performance and deliver understandable reports to managers and directors.
- Defines controls, conversion procedures and system implementation plans including user training and orientation
- Automation processes

DATA ANALYST

Unisys, Mexico, 2019 to 2021

- Power BI reports for managers and board directors
- Reports automation with Python
- Sentiment analysis by NLP
- Data Visualization with Plotly and Dash
- Geospatial analysis with Python Folium maps
- Data wrangling with Databricks notebooks

BIG DATA ENGINEER INDRA, Mexico, 2022 to 2023

- Scala and apache spark big data analysis
- RDD, DataFrames and Datasets manipulation
- Pattern matching
- Data aquisition and manipulation

DATA ANALYST UConn, USA, 2023 present

- Power BI dasboards
- Machine Learning models
- Data Visualization with Plotly and Dash
- Geospatial analysis
- Data engineering with Microsoft Fabric

EDUCATION

INSTITO TECNOLÓGICO AUTÓNOMO DE MÉXICO (ITAM) Masters degree, Data Science, Undergraduate

CENTRO DE CAPACITACION TELEVISIVA Y AUDIOVISUAL (SEP) Big Data Technician, Diploma, 2020

UNIVERSIDAD AUTONOMA METROPOLITANA (UAM) Bachelor's degree, Technologies and Systems Information, 2019

- MySQL databases with Java and PHP, Diploma
- Web developer and Web master for "Espacialidades" Academic Journal

COLEGIO DE CIENCIAS Y HUMANIDADES PLANTEL SUR (CCH) Maintenance and Repair Computer Systems Technician, Diploma, 2012

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL AUTONOMA DE MEXICO (UNAM) Bachelor's degree, Sociology, 2010